Michael Sheleman

Certified Technical Writer | Operations Specialist

sheleman.m@gmail.com (408)607-2116 Redding CA United States https://msheleman.com/portfolio/



SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

With 16 years of experience across three unique industries, I have the robust background to develop and produce any technical documentation your company needs. I'm looking to join an operations team to help grow while mastering my technical writing skills. I love collaborative, chaotic environments and always welcome peer-delivered feedback. So if you're looking for an entrepreneurial spirit who loves to dig in and deliver resolutions, look no further; I'm here to bring out the 'amazing' in your team!

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical & Content Writer | Freelance | Redding, California | From Oct 2020 to present

Managed knowledge database with +7,000 daily views, including establishing theme and design principles.

Translated and compiled release notes for weekly developer releases.

Created engaging and marketable content stories & blogs for clients.

Interim Operations Manager | OnTrac | Redding, California | From Aug 2020 to Oct 2020

Managed all operations for small-package facility delivering +4,000 packages daily.

Managed 12 person sort-team, including onboarding, scheduling, ADP financials, and training paperwork.

Handled two Regional Service Provider delivery teams serving +20 cities.

Operations Specialist - Rebalancer | Motivate LLC | Portland, Oregon Area | From Apr 2019 to Nov 2019

Maintained +95% availability rating across Portland Metro following operation key point indicators.

Completed daily technical documentation for bike repairs and software deployment.

Recorded and produced resolutions for customer feedback across the Portland bicycle fleet.

Product Training Specialist | NAVEX Global | Lake Oswego, Oregon | From May 2018 to Sep 2018

Integrated external Learning Management System into customer knowledge database.

Reduced customer click progression required for accessing SaaS training courses by 66%.

Co-Managed learning knowledge database for the operations department.

Self-Driving Test Operations Specialist | Uber Advanced Technologies Group | San Francisco Bay Area | From Dec 2016 to May 2018

Carried out +2,000hrs of test missions and delivered feedback/completion reports to software development teams.

Co-Developed team documentation for the creation of GIS data-gathering paths across 1,290miles of San Francisco roads.

Built online training modules using authoring tools for training new test vehicle operators on proprietary software.

High-Rise Security Officer | Universal Services of America | San Francisco Bay Area | From Jan 2015 to Dec 2016

Completed Daily Activity and Incident Reports for security operations across three high-rise buildings.

Rebuilt S.O.P. manual to reflect modern security issues, including emerging threats such as drones & digital access-card theft.

Managed Everbridge Emergency Notification database for over 1,000 tenants.

Aviation Life Support Technician | US Army | COB Speicher Iraq - Savannah, Georgia | From Jul 2008 to Jul 2010

Administrated the Office of Life Support for 54 pilot aviation unit.

Managed all documentation for office, including SOPs, bench-stock, parts-acquisition, RMA, and brief reports to superiors.

Performed and recorded aviation unit level inspections on life support equipment.

Cataloged bench stock with 800 serial numbers and 2000 individual parts. Spearheaded operation in Iraq to reconstruct bench-stock systems and logistics after a critical failure during transport.

Apache Helicopter Repair Mechanic/Crewchief | US Army | Savannah, Georgia | COB Speicher, Iraq | Camp Humphreys, South Korea | From Jul 2004 to Jul 2010

Managed and reviewed aircraft maintenance logbooks for 18 different aircraft.

Evaluated and certified technical documentation for inspection, installation, removal, and replacement of aircraft parts.

Interpreted aircraft technical manual and repair schematics for the Apache Longbow.

Coordinated aircraft repair schedule in tandem with twenty-four other aircraft to maintain 24/7 air presence during 2008-2009 operations in Iraq.

EDUCATION

San Francisco State University | https://www.sfsu.edu/ | From Aug 2012 to May 2014

Graduated with 3.63GPA

Shasta College | From Aug 2012 to May 2012

SKILLS

- · Autonomous Vehicles Proficiency: Proficient
- Scrum Master I (PSMI) Proficiency: Proficient
- Technical Writing Proficiency: Proficient
- Google Suite Proficiency: Advanced
- Microsoft Word Microsoft Office Applications Proficiency: Advanced
- Technical Diagram Analysis Proficiency: Advanced
- Adobe Captivate Graphic Design Tools Proficiency: Proficient
- Electronic Component Installation & Repair Proficiency: Proficient
- Adobe Photoshop Graphic Design Tools Proficiency: Proficient
- Asana Project Management Software Proficiency: Proficient
- Atlassian JIRA Bug and Issue Tracking Tools Proficiency: Proficient
- Salesforce Cloud Platforms Proficiency: Proficient
- Trello Project Management Software Proficiency: Proficient
- ADP PC / Payroll Proficiency: Proficient
- eLearning Proficiency: Proficient
- Office Administration Proficiency: Proficient
- Substantive editing Proficiency: Proficient
- Copyediting Proficiency: Proficient
- Proofreading Proficiency: Proficient
- SEO Copywriting Writing Proficiency: Proficient
- Content Creation Content Marketing Proficiency: Proficient

CERTIFICATIONS & MEMBERSHIPS

Certified Professional SCRUM Master™ I (PSM1)

- Certified Professional Technical Communicator (CPTC™)
- Society for Technical Communications Member

JOB SEARCH DETAILS

• Categories of Interest: Entertainment & Media, Internet & Ecommerce, Operations, Online Content, Technical Writing

Job Types: EmployeeSchedules: Full-Time

• Level of Remote Work: Any Level of Remote Work

• Start Date: Flexible

• Availability: Mornings, Afternoons, Weekdays

• Maximum Hours/Week: 40

Job Flexibility Preferences: Remote Work
Willing to Travel: Yes, a bit
Career Level: Experienced
Highest Education Level: Bachelor's Degree